<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-03-25T19:45:17-03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">slvrsluger</title><subtitle>slvrsluger's experimental poker blog</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Hand of the Day - 1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/03/25/hand-of-day" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hand of the Day - 1" /><published>2020-03-25T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2020-03-25T00:00:00-03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/03/25/hand-of-day</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/03/25/hand-of-day">&lt;p&gt;I thought I would start of the &lt;em&gt;Hand of the Day&lt;/em&gt; series with a fun hand that illustrates a point that I have been thinking a lot about recently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;180bb deep with the fun player who straddles to 8bb on our direct left in the cutoff. Folds to us and we pot to 24bb with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/cards/QS.svg#inline&quot; alt=&quot;card-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/cards/QH.svg#inline&quot; alt=&quot;card-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/cards/9S.svg#inline&quot; alt=&quot;card-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/cards/9H.svg#inline&quot; alt=&quot;card-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fun player calls and we see the flop of&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/cards/KH.svg#inline&quot; alt=&quot;card-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/cards/JS.svg#inline&quot; alt=&quot;card-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/cards/4S.svg#inline&quot; alt=&quot;card-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;check, check&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/cards/KH.svg#inline&quot; alt=&quot;card-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/cards/JS.svg#inline&quot; alt=&quot;card-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/cards/4S.svg#inline&quot; alt=&quot;card-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/cards/AC.svg#inline&quot; alt=&quot;card-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;check, fun player bets 2/5 pot, we call&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/cards/KH.svg#inline&quot; alt=&quot;card-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/cards/JS.svg#inline&quot; alt=&quot;card-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/cards/4S.svg#inline&quot; alt=&quot;card-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/cards/AC.svg#inline&quot; alt=&quot;card-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/cards/7C.svg#inline&quot; alt=&quot;card-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;check, fun player bets 1/2 pot, we call and win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea that I have been thinking a lot about is that as a small-stakes professional I am in large part just waiting for fun-players to make blunders and act predictably. In this case predictably continuing with 100%-range preflop and betting only a very narrow slice of that 100% for value on the river gives us an easy call with a hand that I would guess is well into the bottom 50th percentile of absolute hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is not uplifting to realize that a large part of the job is waiting around for unaware gambling hobbyist to act like unaware gambling hobbyist. But what are you going to do. That is the job.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>slvrsluger</name></author><category term=".5/1" /><category term="river" /><category term="srp" /><category term="hu" /><category term="150bb" /><summary type="html">I thought I would start of the Hand of the Day series with a fun hand that illustrates a point that I have been thinking a lot about recently.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Calling 3Bets</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/analysis/2020/03/18/calling_3bets" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Calling 3Bets" /><published>2020-03-18T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2020-03-18T00:00:00-03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/analysis/2020/03/18/calling_3bets</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/analysis/2020/03/18/calling_3bets">&lt;p&gt;I’m old enough to have been around when the &lt;em&gt;revolutionary&lt;/em&gt; idea that you should fold to some three-bets in six-max pot-limit-omaha came about. Revolution had two main tenants. One, Axxx hands did poorly enough against three-betting ranges to warrant a fold. And secondly, that some of the weakest one-way or none-nut hands you open such as raggy kings or the worst of the single suited rundowns couldn’t stand the heart either and should be folded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be quite honest my thinking has not become much more profound than those two points over the last handful of years. Today I reached the point where the little bit of curiosity and immense tiredness of not knowing what to do in this very common spot is leading to some action!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To limit the scope let’s only concern ourselves with optimal play at one rake level and only look at a four situations (small stakes rake; ep v bn, co v bn, bn v sb, co v bb). And before I set off searching for some answers I want to note my predictions - both as an exercise in masochistic imagination and scientific procedure. With that said let’s take a closer look at calling three-bets.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>slvrsluger</name></author><category term="gambit" /><category term="3bp" /><category term="strategy" /><category term="online" /><summary type="html">I’m old enough to have been around when the revolutionary idea that you should fold to some three-bets in six-max pot-limit-omaha came about. Revolution had two main tenants. One, Axxx hands did poorly enough against three-betting ranges to warrant a fold. And secondly, that some of the weakest one-way or none-nut hands you open such as raggy kings or the worst of the single suited rundowns couldn’t stand the heart either and should be folded.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Run It Once - A Reasonable Reason</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/03/06/Run-It-Once-Reason" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Run It Once - A Reasonable Reason" /><published>2020-03-06T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2020-03-06T00:00:00-03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/03/06/Run-It-Once-Reason</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/03/06/Run-It-Once-Reason">&lt;p&gt;Over the years it has become more and more common for online sites and live players to offer to run it more than once (run-it-twice or RIT), meaning that players can agree to play out the remaining cards more than once after all the money is in and more cards are still to come. Also more and more common are ridiculous reasons for a player’s decision to run-it-once or RIT. While I have heard many reasons, only a few are actually reasonable and almost none are logically sound. But I think I have a novel and reasonable reason to run-it-once and only once. (Note: I am aware that most people think their own reasons are reasonable, just hear me out).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In one word, attachment. Both the Buddha’s teachings while wandering the kingdoms of India and Tommy Angelo’s teachings in &lt;em&gt;Painless Poker&lt;/em&gt; agree that attachment is the source of much of our suffering and tilt (for more on that concept see Buddhism or Tommy Angelo). Simply, running-it-twice activates whatever module it is in our brain that has to do with attachment more than is necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As professional gamblers we do not need the distractions that come along with attachment. Yes, while it is true that we are better at dealing with those distractions than are fun-players, we are not wholly immune to them either. Getting it it 60/40, running-it-twice, and splitting comes along with some flavor of &lt;em&gt;won the first one… that’s good… mother fucker… almost scooped&lt;/em&gt;. Rather you could have felt the pain or satisfaction (because we are non-enlightened creature and attached to the outcome, remember) only once and moved on to the next decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my argument is really one of making better decisions. Because in the end that is what our job really is - we try to make the best decisions possible. I claim that less thoughts and feelings related to attachment is a way to do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conclusion, if you are enlightened (I know of only the Buddha and Tommy Angelo) run it twice and reduce variance; otherwise, run-it-once.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Over the years it has become more and more common for online sites and live players to offer to run it more than once (run-it-twice or RIT), meaning that players can agree to play out the remaining cards more than once after all the money is in and more cards are still to come. Also more and more common are ridiculous reasons for a player’s decision to run-it-once or RIT. While I have heard many reasons, only a few are actually reasonable and almost none are logically sound. But I think I have a novel and reasonable reason to run-it-once and only once. (Note: I am aware that most people think their own reasons are reasonable, just hear me out).</summary></entry></feed>